Welcome back to another Shotcut video editing tutorial. In this video we're
欢迎回到另一个ShotCut视频编辑教程 在这段视频中 我们将
going to be learning how to scale and change the size and rotate our video
我将学习如何缩放、更改大小和旋转我们的视频
clips. So I have three clips loaded in here. I'm just going to drag one of them down to
剪辑 所以我在这里装了三个弹夹 我要把他们中的一个拖到
the timeline and we'll zoom in a little bit here. So it is a filter that we're
时间线 我们将在这里放大一点 所以这是一个过滤器 我们是
going to apply to do that. So we go into filters like we've done in the past. We
将会申请这样做 因此 我们像过去一样进入过滤器 我们
click add and then there is a filter and effect for that under video. So the ones
点击Add 然后在视频下面有一个滤镜和效果 所以那些
we're going to be doing is rotate and scale and size and position. So the first
我们要做的是旋转、缩放、大小和位置 所以第一个
one we'll do is just rotate and scale. It's a little bit easier to use in my
我们要做的一件事就是旋转和缩放 它更容易在我的
opinion. So the scaling is just based off a percentage. So it's 100% right now. If
意见 因此 比例调整只是基于百分比 所以现在是100% 如果
we scale it up we can zoom in. If we scale it out we can zoom out a little bit
我们可以放大它 我们可以放大它 如果我们向外扩展 我们可以稍微缩小一点
there and make it smaller. But we can't actually click over here and make any
就在那里 把它变小 但我们实际上不能点击这里并制作任何
changes. We just have these four different options. Scale and we have
改变 我们只有四种不同的选择 规模 我们有
rotation. We can turn it you know 90 degrees, 180 degrees and if we ever want
旋转 我们可以把它转90度 180度 如果我们想的话
to get it back to zero we could try and find exact zero on here or we can just
为了让它回到零 我们可以试着在这里找到精确的零 或者我们可以
click this button and it resets any changes that we've made. So if we want to
单击此按钮 它将重置我们所做的任何更改 所以如果我们想
just reset everything back to how it was we just do that real quick. Offset is
只要把一切都恢复到原来的样子 我们就会非常迅速地完成 偏移量为
going to be basically our position. So that means we can scale up and find a
基本上将是我们的立场 这意味着我们可以纵向扩展并找到
certain point in here. So that's one way to kind of position the video and scale
这里的某个点 这是定位视频和缩放比例的一种方式
it. Okay I want to show you another way to do it. So we'll click the minus sign
它 好的 我想给你展示另一种方法 所以我们要点击减号
we'll get rid of that. Everything's back to how it was. So we'll add in now, scroll
我们会处理掉它的 一切都回到了原来的样子 所以我们现在要加入 滚动
down under video or we can even just type in. Scale and Rotate is what we did.
在视频下面或者我们甚至可以直接输入 缩放和旋转就是我们所做的
So the next one is called size and position. It's not called transform which
所以下一个叫做大小和位置 它不叫变换 不叫变换
is what I'm used to in CaydenLive and some other video editing programs. It's
这是我在CaydenLive和其他一些视频编辑程序中习惯的 它是
called size and position but basically it's similar to transform. This one when
称为大小和位置 但基本上类似于变换 这一次是在
it's applied it does give us some handles. We can click here left click and
它被应用了它确实给了我们一些句柄 我们可以点击这里左键点击
actually move the video around. So kind of accomplishing the same thing as that
将视频移动到各处 就像是完成了同样的事情
offset on the X and Y axis. We can also click these handles and just scale it up
X和Y轴上的偏移量 我们还可以单击这些手柄并将其向上扩展
and down and right now we're doing the size mode is set to fill which means
向下 现在我们正在做大小模式设置为填充 这意味着
it's going to scale according to whatever I it's going to keep the X and
它将根据任何I进行扩展 它将保持X和
Y axis the same. So it's not going to distort but if we click distort then we
Y轴相同 所以它不会扭曲 但如果我们点击扭曲 那么我们
actually can scale and make this like very skinny. But if we want to reset
实际上可以扩大规模 让它看起来很瘦 但如果我们想要重置
that we can just reset everything. See as I move these it's actually changing
我们可以重新设置一切 看 当我移动这些东西时 它实际上正在改变
these numbers over here. The position and the size. So if I move this one it moves
这些数字在这里 位置和大小 所以如果我移动这个 它就会移动
just the position on the X and Y. So I can come over here and put a 2 in and it
就是在X和Y上的位置 所以我可以在这里加上一个2
moves it over here. I can put an 8 in it'll move it over here towards the
把它移到这里来 我可以加一个8 它会把它移到这里
right and so I can change the size as well. This way I can have it be we'll
好的 所以我也可以改变尺寸 这样我就能拥有它 我们将
change this one to 400 and then it's like much smaller. Anyway I can reset
把这个改成400 然后它就小多了 不管怎样 我可以重置
all of these back to how they were by default. There's also this little button
所有这些都回到了默认的状态 还有一个小按钮
here which sets a key frame. We'll learn about this in the future but this lets
这里设置了一个关键帧 我们将在未来了解这一点 但这让我们
us actually change the position and move that position so we could have our video
我们实际上改变了位置 移动了那个位置 这样我们就可以看到我们的视频了
like slowly animate and move across the screen. So check out a future tutorial
就像慢慢地在屏幕上移动动画一样 因此 请查看未来的教程
learning how to use key frames. You can do the same thing with the with the
学习如何使用关键帧 您可以用来做同样的事情
Rotate and Scale as well. So Rotate and Scale has these options here. We click it
也可以旋转和缩放 因此 旋转和缩放在这里有这些选项 我们点击它
and it adds a key frame down here and we can actually have different we'll learn
它在这里增加了一个关键帧 我们实际上可以有不同的 我们将学习
how to do that in the future. So don't worry about that just click on it again
在未来如何做到这一点 所以不用担心 只需再次点击它
and you can just get rid of it. Anyway that is size and position. Go ahead and
你可以干脆把它处理掉 无论如何 这就是大小和位置 去吧 然后
play with those. Oh and right now I have both applied. Just so you know you can
玩那些吧 哦 现在我两个都申请了 只是想让你知道你可以
have both applied at the same time. So we can rotate this and then come into our
都是同时申请的 所以我们可以旋转这个 然后进入我们的
size and position and then we can move it on within there but it gets a little
大小和位置 然后我们可以把它移到那里 但它会变得有点
bit crazy. So see right now because it's because we've rotated it's doing it we're
有点疯狂 所以现在看到了 因为我们旋转了它 我们正在做它
moving at kind of one within the other and we can actually rotate we can move
以一种在另一种中移动 我们可以旋转 我们可以移动
this and see which one has priority as well. Whether we have rotate on top or
这一点 看看哪一个也优先 无论我们是在顶部旋转还是
size and position it'll do whatever whatever filter it gets to first is what
大小和位置它会做任何过滤 它首先是什么
gets processed first. So just be aware that can happen. I would recommend
首先得到处理 所以 只要知道这是可能发生的就行了 我会推荐
sticking with one or the other and not both. But that is using yeah scale, rotate,
坚持其中之一 而不是两个都坚持 但这是在使用缩放、旋转、
size, position. It's a filter in Shotcut. Go ahead and play with those and the more
大小 位置 这是ShotCut中的滤镜 去玩吧 玩那些 还有更多
you use them the more familiar you'll get with them. If you have any questions
你越使用它们 你就越熟悉它们 如果您有任何问题
let me know. I'll do my best to answer them and I sincerely thank you for
让我知道 我会尽我所能回答他们 我真诚地感谢你
watching and look forward to seeing you in future tutorials.
关注并期待在未来的教程中与您见面